Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm 5863 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- RG 60 - Straight Numerical File (Reel 6)
  - 0356. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 58. Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 51 pages., 1918-1919; 4 (Reel 6)
    People: A. Mitchell Palmer; C.E.S. Wood; Louise Olivereau; Marie Equi; Anna Louise Strong; John Lord O'Brian; Alfred Bettman; Clarence L. Reames; Harry Weinberger; Thomas W. Gregory; Thomas Nolan. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Seattle, Washington, and Saint Michael, Alaska; Espionage Act prosecutions; Department of Justice policies regarding clemency for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; surveillance and censorship of mail of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the Colorado State Penitentiary.
  - 0407. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 59. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World Cases. 129 pages., 1918-1919; 5 (Reel 6)
    People: A. Mitchell Palmer; Henry B. Twombly; Theodora Pollok; Claude R. Porter; Annette Abbott Adams; William Kent; W. C. Coghlan; G. S. Arnold; Robert Scott; Alfred Bettman; John W. Preston; Mortimer Downing; John Lord O'Brian; George M. La Monte; Louise Connolly; Jeannette Rankin; Thomas W. Gregory; Joseph P. Tumulty; Simon J. Lubin; George L. Bell; George N. Murdock; Woodrow W. Wilson; Robert Duncan; William C. Fitts; P. H. Johnson. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California; protests against prosecution of Theodora Pollok; Department of Justice policies regarding clemency for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; California District Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World.
  - 0536. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 5. Previously Restricted Materials. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 6 pages., 1918; 6 (Reel 6)
    People: Claude R. Porter; John W. Preston; Robert Duncan; George F. Vanderveer; George N. Murdock; P. H. Johnson; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California; Bureau of Investigation reports on progress of cases.
  - 0542. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 60. Detroit, Michigan, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 15 pages., 1917; 7 (Reel 6)
    People: E. C. Davison; William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski; Thomas W. Gregory; Arnold Petersen; S. G. Bargery. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Detroit, Michigan; International Association of Machinists complaints regarding seizure of local union records in Department of Justice raids; misuse of search warrants in Department of Justice raids on Socialist Labor party offices in Detroit, Michigan, and Columbus, Ohio.
  - 0557. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 60. Previously Restricted Materials. Detroit, Michigan, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 45 pages., 1917-1918; 8 (Reel 6)
    People: William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski; William D. Haywood; S. G. Bargery; Delmas C. Stutler. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Detroit, Michigan, misuse of search warrants in Department of Justice raids on Socialist Labor party offices in Detroit, Michigan, and Columbus, Ohio.
  - 0602. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Russian Consul at Seattle, Washington. 30 pages., 1917-1918; 9 (Reel 6)
    People: Fred H. Moore; Thomas W. Gregory; John Lord O'Brian; Frank L. Polk; William C. Fitts; Hugh C. Wallace; Woodrow W. Wilson, George F. Vanderveer; M. E. Saville. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Soviet Russian Consulate at Seattle, Washington; emigrants to Soviet Russia; Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of State regarding complaints against activities of Soviet Russian Consulate at Seattle, Washington; Industrial Workers of the World and pro- German activities in the Pacific Northwest.
  - 0632. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 61. Previously Restricted Materials. Russian Consul at Seattle, Washington. 2 pages., 1918; 10 (Reel 6)
    People: John Lord O'Brian; A. B. Bielaski; William C. Fitts; Fred H. Moore. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Soviet Russian Consulate at Seattle, Washington; emigrants to Soviet Russia.
  - 0634. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 62. Portland, Oregon, Industrial Workers of the World case. 3 pages., 1918; 11 (Reel 6)
    People: Emma Goldman; Alexander Berkman. Subject: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Portland, Oregon.
  - 0637. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 63. Fort Meade, Maryland, case. 2 pages., 1918; 12 (Reel 6)
    People: Walter Mills Hinkle. Subject: Protest regarding radical enroute to Soviet Russia as employee of the Young Men's Christian Association.
  - 0639. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 64. Roanoke, Virginia, case. 3 pages., 1918; 13 (Reel 6)
    People: William C. Fitts; Woodrow W. Wilson. Subject: Department of Justice policy regarding prosecution of remarks mage against President Wilson.
  - 0642. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 65. Marshfield, Oregon, case. 7 pages., 1918; 14 (Reel 6)
    People: Not available. Subject: Workers Socialist Publishing Company, Duluth, Minnesota, foreign language circulars seized by United States Post Office Department in Marshfield, Oregon.
  - 0649. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 66. Coeur d'Alene, Idaho, Industrial Workers of the World case. 7 pages., 1918-1919; 15 (Reel 6)
    People: Neil Guiney; William C. Fitts; Frank K. Nebeker; Claude r. Porter. Subject: Department of Justice receipt of transcript of evidence in Idaho state Industrial Workers of the World prosecution.
  - 0656. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 67. Sheffield, Alabama, Industrial Workers of the World Case. 5 pages., 1918; 16 (Reel 6)
    People: William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski. Subject: Citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Sheffield, Alabama.
  - 0661. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 68. S. 4471, 65th Congress, 2nd Session. 11 pages., 1918; 17 (Reel 6)
    People: William H. King; John Lord O'Brian. Subjects: Department of Justice policy regarding wartime anti-Industrial Workers of the World legislation before the United States Congress; Espionage Act prosecutions.
  - 0672. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 70. Salt Lake City, Utah, Industrial Workers of the World case. 7 pages., 1919; 18 (Reel 6)
    People: Claude R. Porter; Oscar W. Larson. Subjects: Department of Justice policy regarding the release of literature seized in Military Intelligence Division raids on Industrial Workers of the World offices in salt Lake City, Utah; mass meetings in Seattle, Washington.
  - 0679. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 71. Tacoma and Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 21 pages., 1919; 19 (Reel 6)
    People: Robert C. Saunders; Claude R. Porter; Clarence L. Reames; A. Mitchell Palmer; Louis F. Hart. Subjects: Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in immigration and deportation cases; protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Tacoma, Washington; wartime activities of the Bureau of Investigation in Seattle, Washington; general strikes; planned Industrial Workers of the World activities at the Washington State Federation of Labor convention to be held in Bellingham, Washington.
  - 0700. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 73. E. F. Doree. 5 pages., 1919; 20 (Reel 6)
    People: E. F. Doree; A. Mitchell Palmer. Subject: Protest against planned Industrial Workers of the World General Defense Committee fund raising meeting in Devils Lake, North Dakota.
  - 0705. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 74, Part 1. Centralia and Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 213 pages., 1919; 21 (Reel 6)
    People: A. Mitchell Palmer; Anna B. Field; William D. Haywood; Louis F. Hart; Robert C. Saunders; Robert Scott; William B. Wilson; William Short; Samuel Gompers. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Centralia and Seattle, Washington; veteran's organizations; Woman's International Union Label League; American Legion; Veterans of Foreign wars of the United States; Grand Army of the Republic; Department of Justice cooperation with United states Department of Labor in immigration and deportation cases; Department of Justice prosecution of the Seattle Union Record; general strikes; Industrial Workers of the World infiltration of the American Federation of Labor in the Pacific Northwest; protests against lynching of Wesley Everest in Centralia, Washington; protests against Department of Justice raid on Seattle Union Record office; conference of state, local, federal prosecutors in Washington; Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Centralia, Washington; United States Post Office Department censorship of publications.
  - 0918. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 74, Part 2. Centralia and Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 332 pages., 1919-1921; 22 (Reel 6)
    People: Wesley Everest; E.T. Doran; William D. Haywood; George F. Vanderveer; Elmer S. Smith; Robert c. Saunders; Alexander C. King; E.P. Ault; George P. Listman; F.A. Rust; Anna Louise Strong; Joseph P. Tumulty; Charles D. Fullen; A. Mitchell Palmer; George Williams; Sidney L Gulick; Newton D. Baker; Josephus Daniels; Robert Scott; William Short; Paul U. Kellogg; Robert Minor. Subject: Protests against lynching of Wesley Everest and anti-Industrial Workers of the World activities in Centralia, Washington; mass meetings; General defense Committee and Northwest Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; Department of Justice Cooperation with Washington state prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Centralia, Washington; Department of Justice prosecution of the Seattle Union Record; Espionage Act prosecutions; veteran's organizations; protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Centralia, Washington; requests for clemency in Department of Justice prosecution of Anna Louise Strong and other editors of the Seattle Union Record; American Legion; decisions on demurrers and indictments in Seattle Union record cases; general strikes; Washington State Federation of Labor.
- RG 60 - Straight Numerical File (Reel 7)
  - 0000. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 74, Part 3. Centralia and Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 30 pages, 1924-1925; 1 (Reel 7)
    People: William J. Donovan. Subjects: Protests against Washington state prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Centralia, Washington; requests for Department of Justice intervention and affidavits of jurors and witnesses in case; American Legion; veteran's organizations.
  - 0030. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 75. Industrial Workers of the World propaganda in Mexico. 4 pages., 1919; 2 (Reel 7)
    People: Not available. Subjects: Industrial workers of the World propaganda and organization of coal miners in Coahuila, Mexico; United States Department of State cooperation with Department of Justice.
  - 0034. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 76. Providence, Rhode Island. 1 page., 1919; 3 (Reel 7)
    People: Not available. Subject: Not available.
  - 0035. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 92. William z. Foster. 4 pages., 1921; 4 (Reel 7)
    People: Harry M. Daugherty; Willis F. McCook; William Z. Foster. Subject: Protests against speaking tour of William Z. Foster.
  - 0039. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 103. Nicholas Radivoeff. 20 pages., 1921-1922; 5 (Reel 7)
    People: Nicholas Radivoeff; James J. Davis; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Butte, Montana, habeas corpus proceedings; Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in immigration and deportation cases.
  - 0059. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 104. Joseph Yeager. 8 pages., 1920; 6 (Reel 7)
    People: Joseph Yeager. Subjects: Request for information regarding whereabouts of former Industrial Workers of the World and Western Federation Miners member from Arizona.
  - 0067. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 213. James Price. 5 pages., 1921; 7 (Reel 7)
    People: James Price. Subject: Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in immigration and naturalization cases.
  - 0072. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 227. Simon J. Lubin. 4 pages., 1918; 8 (Reel 7)
    People: Simon J. Lubin; Thomas W. Gregory; Woodrow W. Wilson; George L. Bell. Subjects: State Commission of Immigration and Housing of California; requests for investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in California; Pacific Coast governors request for suppression of the Industrial Workers of the World.
  - 0076. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 237. E.T. Doran. 2 pages., 1921; 9 (Reel 7)
    People: E.T. Doran. Subject: Planned speaking engagement of E.T. Doran at Centralia, Washington.
  - 0078. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 269. Ray Becker. 11 pages., 1926-1927; 10 (Reel 7)
    People: Ray Becker; George F. Vanderveer. Subjects: Protests against Washington State prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Centralia, Washington; prison conditions at Walla Walla, Washington, state penitentiary; legal defense efforts; General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; pen pals of prisoners; American Legion.
  - 0089. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 276. Joe Dezelin. 5 pages., 1921; 11 (Reel 7)
    People: Joe Dezelin; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in North Carolina; immigrant labor; labor agencies.
  - 0094. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 319. Thomas Rimmer. 2 pages., 1921; 12 (Reel 7)
    People: Thomas Rimmer. Subjects: Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of State; Industrial Workers of the World activities in Butte, Montana.
  - 0096. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 355. C. R. James. 4 pages., 1921; 13 (Reel 7)
    People: C.R. James. Subject: Protest against Industrial Workers of the World activities among blacks in New York City.
  - 0100. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 356. Railroad Travel Arrangements of Industrial Workers of the World organizers in Washington. 30 pages., 1922; 14 (Reel 7)
    People: Not available. Subjects: Cooperation between railroad employees and Industrial Workers of the World organizers in securing free travel on freight trains in Washington; affidavits of hoboes regarding Industrial Workers of the World organization of hoboes and railroad employees; sale of Industrial Workers of the World membership cards to riders of freight trains.
  - 0130. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 357. G. Rudolph Bickert. 5 pages., 1922; 15 (Reel 7)
    People: G. Rudolph Bickert. Subject: Request for ruling of Department of Justice on legality of Industrial Workers of the World membership.
  - 0135. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 358. Industrial Workers of the World strike plans in California. 6 pages., 1923; 16 (Reel 7)
    People: Not available. Subject: Industrial Workers of the World organization and strike plans among railroad employees in California.
  - 0141. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 359. Industrial Workers of the World strike plans in California and Texas. 1 page., 1923; 17 (Reel 7)
    People: Not available. Subject: Industrial Workers of the World organization and strike plans among railroad employees in California and Texas. File folder omitted.
  - 0142. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 359. Previously Restricted Materials. Industrial Workers of the World Strike Plans in California and Texas. 1 page., 1923; 18 (Reel 7)
    People: J. Edgar Hoover. Subject: Industrial Workers of the World organization and strike plans among railroad employees in California and Texas.
  - 0143. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 360. Industrial Workers of the World activities among United States Veterans' Bureau hospital employees in Arizona. 5 pages., 1923; 19 (Reel 7)
    People: Not available. Subject: Industrial Workers of the World organization of United States Veterans' Bureau hospital employees in California and Texas.
  - 0148. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 5. California. 5 pages., 1917; 20 (Reel 7)
    People: Frank K. Nebeker; J. Robert O'Connor; Thomas W. Gregory; John W. Preston. Subjects: Cooperation in Department of Justice prosecutions of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in California and Chicago, Illinois; immigrant labor in California; arson and acts of incendiarism in California.
  - 0153. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 6. Colorado. 5 pages., 1918-1919; 21 (Reel 7)
    People: Harry B. Tedrow; William C. Fitts. Subject: Bureau of Investigation agents in Colorado; Department of Justice raids on Industrial Workers of the World offices in Denver.
  - 0158. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 15. Indiana. 3 pages., 1917-1927; 22 (Reel 7)
    People: George N. Murdock; A.B. Bielaski; J. Edgar Hoover; William J. Donovan. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation; coal mine operators; American Legion.
  - 0161. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 17. Kansas. 2 pages., 1920; 23 (Reel 7)
    People: J. Edgar Hoover. Subjects: Department of Justice policy regarding Industrial Workers of the World publications; Department of Justice raids in Minnesota.
  - 0163. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 19. Louisiana. 1 page., 1920; 24 (Reel 7)
    People: J. Edgar Hoover. Subject: Department of Justice investigations of Industrial Workers of the World activities.
  - 0164. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 21. Maryland. 1 page., 1920; 25 (Reel 7)
    People: J. Edgar Hoover. Subject: Protests regarding Industrial Workers of the World activities in Maryland.
  - 0165. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 22. Massachusetts. 2 pages., 1917; 26 (Reel 7)
    People: William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski; George W. Anderson. Subjects: Private detective agencies; Bureau of Investigation.
  - 0167. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 24. Minnesota. 6 pages., 1918-1920; 27 (Reel 7)
    People: J. Edgar Hoover; Claude R. Porter. Subjects: Department of Justice raids in Minnesota; Industrial Workers of the World activities in Minnesota.
  - 0173. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 26. Missouri.3 pages., 1918; 28 (Reel 7)
    People: Claude R. Porter; A.B. Bielaski; William C. Fitts; George F. Vanderveer; Antone Johanson; Frank P. Walsh. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World organization of oil workers; Oil Workers Industrial Union; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Department of Justice raids; Bureau of Investigation; Department of Justice surveillance of mail of attorneys for Industrial Workers of the World defendants.
  - 0176. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 27. Montana. 32 pages., 1917-1921; 29 (Reel 7)
    People: J. Edgar Hoover; Benjamin H. Fletcher; George Hardy; Thomas W. Gregory; Burton K. Wheeler; Frank Little. Subjects: Department of Justice surveillance of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Butte, Montana; mass meetings; industrial unionism; organization of black Americans in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; emigrants to Soviet Russia; Industrial Workers of the World factionalism and internal politics; Department of Justice cooperation with local prosecutions of Industrial Workers of the World defendants; Industrial Workers of the World organization of smelter workers, copper miners, coal miners, and lumber workers in Montana; Finnish immigrants; citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Montana; protests against lynching of Industrial Workers of the World executive board member Frank Little in Butte, Montana; strikes.
  - 0208. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 28. Nebraska. 5 pages., 1918-1919; 30 (Reel 7)
    People: Claude R. Porter. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Nebraska and Kansas; Bureau of Investigation.
  - 0213. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 29. Nevada. 2 pages., 1917-1919; 31 (Reel 7)
    People: A. B. Bielaski. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World organization of miners in Nevada; strike plans.
  - 0215. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 45. Texas. 12 pages., 1917-1923; 32 (Reel 7)
    People: William J. Burns; Arthur Caminetti; J. Edgar Hoover; William C. Fitts; Thomas W. Gregory; A. B. Bielaski. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation; Department of Justice cooperation with local prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants and seizures of Industrial Workers of the World documents; Department of Justice cooperation with Military Intelligence Division; Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities among immigrant labor in Texas; Industrial Workers of the World organization of shipyard workers, seamen, and oil workers in Texas, Oklahoma, and Mexico; protests against enclosing of rangeland in Texas.
  - 0227. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 46. Utah. 2 pages., 1917; 33 (Reel 7)
    People: A. B. Bielaski; William C. Fitts; Frank K. Nebeker; Grover H. Perry. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities among mine workers, smelter workers, railroad workers, and agricultural workers in Utah and Arizona; strikes.